# Samuel Griffin

smgriffin0@gmail.com 608-235-7030 linkedin.com/in/smgriffin0/

## **Summary**

Recent science communication master's graduate with 5 years' experience in science program management and conducting research with a proven track record in managing projects for multidisciplinary teams, supporting organizational objectives and operations. Enthusiastic, self-motivated, strategic thinker seeking digital communications opportunities.

## **Core Competencies and Skills**

Content Management Systems: WordPress, Drupal, GitHub Pages Programming Languages: CSS, HTML, python, R, SQL

Web Analytics Tools: Google Analytics

Other: Project Management Internal/External Communication

Adobe Creative Suite G Suite, keynote, canva Public Relations Customer Experience

## **Experience**

# Eliceiri Group, aka Laboratory for Optical and Computational Instrumentation, Madison, WI

Digital Communications Specialist & Administrator

10/2018 - present

- Designed and project managed creation of eight Center for Quantitative Cell Imaging affiliated websites.
- Ensured website conformity with organization and accessibility web standards.
- Produced news stories, web content, and graphic deliverables for center social media channels.
- Redesigned laboratory YouTube channel, leading to 90% increase in subscribers after 1 year.
- Created repository for personnel health reports, maintaining confidentiality and increasing unit audit security.
- Designed, drafted, and published internal and external communications showcasing research value.
- Created branded poster template toolkits, leading to decreased duplication of efforts and increased efficiency.
- Develop professional relationships with external campus departments, fostering collaboration with enthusiasm.
- Served in leadership capacity for day-to-day lab operations.

#### Carroll Lab, Howard Hughes Medical Institute, Madison, WI

Communications Working Group Member

08/2022 - present

- Collaborate with peers on projects including monthly newsletters to highlight organizational value.
- Collaborate on communications campaigns contributing to a 100% membership increase from 2021 to 2022.
- Managed creation of new conference website using agile development.
- Draft white paper discussing unique organizational benefits as part of recruitment campaign.
- Served on organizing committee for international academic meetings.
- Provide feedback on internal and external organization communications to executive stakeholders.

## **Howard Hughes Medical Institute**

Research Technician

07/2015 - 06/2018

- Designed and implemented innovative protocols for efficient, high-throughput BAC clone screening.
- Generated reports and presented results to managing postdoc.
- Supported the research activities of the laboratory s postdocs and principal investigator.

#### **Education**

## University of Wisconsin, Madison

Master of Science - Life Sciences Communication

• GPA: 4.0

• Thesis: Framing Climate Mitigation Policy Appeals with GPT

#### University of Wisconsin, Madison

05/2015

Bachelor of Science - Biology & English Literature

• Associate Editor, The Madison Review

#### **Publications**

- Giorgianni MW, Dowell NL, Griffin S, et al. (2020) The origin and diversification of a novel protein family in venomous snakes PNAS 117 (20) 10911-10920. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1920011117
- Dowell NL, Giorgianni MW, Griffin S, et al. (2018) Extremely Divergent Haplotypes in Two Toxin Gene Complexes Encode Alternative Venom Types within Rattlesnake Species. Current Biology 2:28(7):1016-1026.e4. doi:1016/j.cub.2018.02.031 BioImaging North America (BINA), Remote

09/2023